# **Skyler Schuck**

skyler.schuck@state.co.us | skylerschuck.github.io | linkedin.com/in/skyler-schuck/

#### **About Me**

Experience in applied economic analysis & forecasting, budget analysis, and data analysis. A seasoned user in R, SQL, and Python. My research interests include regional analysis and improving rural outcomes. Most of my projects are centered around creating data/information systems and tools to support my research.

#### **Education**

2021 – 2023	M.S., Agricultural and Resource Economics, Colorado State University  Emphasis  Environmental and Natural Resource Economics  Thesis ☑  Exploring the Overall, Distributional and Resiliency Implications of Investments in Rural Constraints The Case of Fishers Peak State Park ☑	
2017 - 2021	Tourism: The Case of Fishers Peak State Park ☑  B.S., Computer Information Systems, California Lutheran University  Magna Cum Laude, GPA: 3.8	
2017 – 2021	<b>B.A., Economics,</b> <i>California Lutheran University</i> Magna Cum Laude, GPA: 3.8	

## **Professional Experience**

01/2023 – present Denver, CO	Economist & Budget Analyst, State of Colorado In the Tax & Economic Development Division in the Governor's Office of State Planning & Budgeting. Economist duties include: quarterly forecasting, data management and visualization, economic and revenue inquiries, & modeling development. Budget Analyst duties include: budget development, budget projections, & legislative analysis.		
08/2021 - 05/2023	Graduate Research Assistant, Colorado State Univesity		
Fort Collins, CO	Apart of the Regional Economic Development Institute (REDI) at CSU. Generate regional economic analysis for on-going projects and as-needed when requested by City/County/State Agencies.		

Leading website re-design project for more interactive and engaging experience. Primary tools and skills include: R, Python, SQL, econometric analysis, optimization, and WordPress.

01/2022 - 01/2023 **Data Science Intern,** City and County of Denver Denver, CO Housed within the Department of Finance, major duties include generating economic analysis, forecasts, and data science reports for internal and external uses. Internal reports include economic outlook and forecast presentations to the City Council and the Mayor. External facing work includes creating economic indicator dashboards. Daily tasks also include data cleaning, visualization generation, natural language processing (NLP), data mining, named entity recognition (NER), and general consulting with other departments within the city. Primary tools and skills include: R, Python, SQL, Power BI, Visual Basic, ArcGIS, and econometric analysis.

05/2022 - 08/2022 Data Engineer Intern, Transamerica Denver, CO Working within Life Technology in Technology Services, I worked on data and API engineering projects using AWS(API Gateway, Lambda, DynamoDB, etc.) and Java (Spring Boot REST API) for maintenance and feature creation for the Financial Services Agent's web services portal. Other core dependencies include Git, JIRA, Terraform, Jenkins, Python, and agile development.

## **Publications**

12/2021

Fishers Peak State Park: Evaluating a New Natural Amenity in Southern Colorado,

REDI@CSU 🛮

The recently christened Fishers Peak State Park offers great potential to give a much-needed boost to the economy of Las Animas County, specifically the town of Trinidad.

### **Skills**

• • • •	Economic Forecasting	• • • •
	Public Budgeting	• • • • •
• • • • •	3	
	Python	$\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$
$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$	Pandas, Pystat, Jupyter	
	AWS	$\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$
$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$	API Gateway, Lambda, DynamoDB	
	••••	Public Budgeting  Python Pandas, Pystat, Jupyter  AWS

#### Courses

**Public Budgeting and Finance,** Colorado State University

**Optimization Methods,** Colorado State University

**Quantitative Methods,** Colorado State University

**Applied Econometrics,** Colorado State University

**Applied Microeconomic Theory,** Colorado State University

**Applied Welfare and Policy Analysis,** Colorado State University

**Environmental and Natural Resource Economics,** *Colorado State University* 

**Applied Advanced Water Resource Economics,** Colorado State University

**Database Management Systems,** *California Lutheran University* 

**Data Analysis with R,** California Lutheran University

**Software Engineering,** California Lutheran University

**Systems Analysis,** California Lutheran University

**Information, Systems, and Organizational Design,** California Lutheran University

## Organizations

**National Association of State Budget Officers,** Associate Member